Guide to the Walter Wilson Greg Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Walter Wilson Greg papers
1495-1959
1905-1959
OSB MSS 162
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
5
(15 boxes)
The papers contain correspondence, printed material, writings and other papers documenting the scholarly career of Walter Wilson Greg, particularly his work on the Bibilography of the English Printed Drama (BEPD), his book reviews and his periodical articles concerning the editing of Shakespeare.
Greg, W. W. (Walter Wilson), 1875-1959
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Please consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Associated Materials
Printed works that were acquired with the Walter Wilson Greg Papers were removed and cataloged separately. A list of these works that contain Greg correspondence or manuscript notes is given in the Appendix to this finding aid. Full catalog records for these items may be found in ORBIS, the Yale University Library catalog.
Walter Wilson Greg (1875-1959)
Walter Wilson Greg, bibliographer and literary scholar, was born in Wimbledon Common, England, on July 9, 1875. He was the only child of the idustrialist and author William Rathbone Greg and Julia Wilson Greg, daughter of James Wilson, the founder of The Economist. Greg's family hoped that he would assume the editorship of the newspaper someday, and he was educated at Harrow School and at Trinity College, Cambridge, from which he received a "pass" degree in 1897.
During his time at Trinity, Greg became fascinated by bibliography and textual editing, studying with R. B. McKerrow, and in 1898 he joined the Bibliographical Society and began a lifelong friendship with its secretary, A. W. Pollard. He served as Librarian of Trinity College from 1907 until 1913, when he resigned upon marrying his cousin Elizabeth Gaskell. Greg never held an official academic appointment again, but his family fortune enabled him to pursue his productive scholarly career for several decades.
Greg founded the Malone Society, serving first as its Secretary, and then as its President; the society during his tenure published more than one hundred editions and facsimile editions of English plays and dramatic documents written prior to 1640. He is best known for his A Bibliography of the English Printed Drama to the Restoration (4 volumes, 1939-1959); his other publications include English Literary Autographs, 1550–1650 (1925–32), Dramatic Documents from the Elizabethan Playhouses (1931), the parallel-text edition Marlowe's 'Doctor Faustus', 1604–1616 (1950), and the influential The Editorial Problem in Shakespeare (revised 3rd edition, 1954).
Greg received many literary and academic honors, including a D.Litt. from Oxford and foreign membership in the American Philosophical Society. In 1950 he was knighted "for services to the study of English literature." He died at home in River, Sussex, in 1959, survived by his wife and their three children.
Scope and Contents
The Walter Wilson Greg Papers document the scholarly career of bibliographer and textual editor Walter Wilson Greg, particularly his work on the multi-volume A Bibliography of the English Printed Drama to the Restoration (4 volumes, 1939-1959). Materials relating to this work include working papers, photostats, prints, and the plate illustrations for Volume I as well as correspondence with other scholars and editors on bibliographical subjects and on the works of Shakespeare. The collection also contains copies of book reviews and scholarly articles by Greg, as well as offprints of articles by his colleagues, often inscribed to Greg, and manuscripts of several articles and lectures, including "The Elements of Textual Criticism in Shakespeare's Plays" and "What Is Bibliography?"
Series IX contains a few personal items, including an unfavorable school report from Harrow School. Series X, Miscellaneous Manuscript Fragments and Documents, contains material Greg collected in the course of his research, perhaps as paleography specimens. Some of the documents date from the sixteenth and seventeenth centuries.
Arrangement
Organized into fourteen series: I. Personal Copies of Greg's Own Reviews, 1922-1957. II. Personal Copies of Colleagues' Articles, 1921-1960. III. Contributions to the Modern Language Review, Volumes I-XV, 1905-1920. IV. Greg's Contributions to The Library, Volumes I-IX, 1900-1909. V. Greg's Personal Copy of Gentleman's Magazine, Volume CCC, 1906. VI. Plates I-CXXXVII from Volume I of Bibliography of English Printed Drama ( BEPD ), 1939-1959. VII. Prints of Title Pages and Portraits, 1800-1959. VIII. Manuscripts of Greg's Articles and Lectures; Lists, 1925-1959. IX. Personal Family Items and Photographs, 1910-1950. X. Miscellaneous Manuscript Fragments and Documents, 1559-1950. XI.Correspondence, 1905-1959. XII. Working Papers, BEPD Volumes I-II, 1939-1954. XIII. Working Papers, projects other than BEPD, 1940-1956. XIV. Photostats, Manuscript and Printed.
English drama -- Bibliography; English drama -- Early modern and Elizabethan, 1500-1600 -- Criticism, Textual; English drama -- Early modern and Elizabethan, 1500-1600; Scholars -- Great Britain; Adams, Joseph Quincy, 1881-1946; Chambers, E. K. (Edmund Kerchever), 1866-1954; Davin, Dan, 1913-1990; Fane, Francis, Sir, -1689? -- Autograph; Ferguson, F. S. (Frederic Sutherland), 1878-1967; Greg, W. W. (Walter Wilson), 1875-1959; McManaway, James Gilmer, 1899-1980; Nash, Ray, 1905-1982; Pollard, Alfred W. (Alfred William), 1859-1944; Scholderer, Walter; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616 ( Bibliography); Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616 ( Criticism, Textual); Simpson, Evelyn Mary Spearing, 1885-1963; Sisam, Kenneth, 1887-; Suckling, John, Sir, 1609-1642 -- Autograph; Walker, Emery, 1851-1933; Wilson, F. P. (Frank Percy), 1889-1963; Bibliographical Society (Great Britain); Malone Society
- Personal Copies of Greg's Own Reviews, 1922-1957; Series I; 0.42; (1 box)
  Arrangement
  The material is arranged in no particular order.
  Scope and Contents
  The series contains offprints and clippings of book reviews written by Walter Wilson Greg, identified by the titles of the works reviewed. Most concern Shakespeare or other late medieval or early modern authors.
  - (Studies in Bibliography) Papers of the Biblio- graphical Society, University of Virginia. Fredson Bowers (Ed.) Vol. 1 (1948) The Modern Language Review v. XLV n. 1 January 1950. (Box 1)
  - IBID Vol. III (1950) MLR v. XLVI n. 3-4 July, October 1951. (Box 1)
  - IBID Vol. 2 (1949-50) MLR v. XLV n. 4 October 1950 [with proof]. (Box 1)
  - IBID Vol. 3 (1950) MLR [proof]. (Box 1)
  - IBID Vol. 4 (1951) MLR V. [proof]. (Box 1)
  - The Great Folio of 1625. Shakespeare's Plays in the printing house. John W. Schroeder (1956) The Book Collector VI, 95 Spr. 1957. (Box 1)
  - A check list of English Plays 1641-1700. Woodward and McManaway (1946) The Library v. I n. 1 June 1946. (Box 1)
  - Encyclopedic Francaise. La Civilisation Ecrite Julian Cain (Ed.) (1939) The Library. (Box 1)
  - The Dramatic Works of Thomas Dekker. Fredson Bowers (Ed.) Vol. 1 (1953) The Review of English Studies v. V n. 20 October 1954. (Box 1)
  - IBID, Vol. 2 (1955) Res v. VII n. 27 July 1956. [See: Greg's Personal Copy of Bower's Book]. (Box 1)
  - Ben Jonson. Herford and Simpson (Eds.) Vols. I-II (1925) MLR v. XXI n. 2 April 1926. (Box 1)
  - IBID Vol. III (1927) MLR v. XXIII n. 1 January 1928. (Box 1)
  - IBID Vol. V (1937) Res v. 14 n. 54 April 1938, Vol. 4 Res v. 9 n. 33 (Jan 33). (Box 1)
  - IBID Vol. VI (1938) Res v. 14 n. 55 July 1938. (Box 1)
  - IBID Vol. VIII (1947) Res v. 24 n. 93 January 1948. (Box 1)
  - IBID Vols. IX and X (1950) Res v. 2 n. 7 July 1951 [with proofs]. (Box 1)
  - IBID Vol. XI (1952) Res v. IV n. 15 July 1953 [with proofs]. (Box 1)
  - Religious Lyrics of the XVth Century. Carleton Brown (Ed.) (1939) Res v. 16 n. 32 April 1940. (Box 1)
  - A Census of Shakespeare's Plays in Quarto 1594-1709. Bartlett and Pollard (1939) Res v. 16 n. 62 April 1940. (Box 1)
  - Elizabethan Book-Pirates. Cyril Bathurst Judge (1934) Res v. 11 n. 44 October 1935. (Box 1)
  - Specimens of Sixteenth-Century English handwriting, Taken from Contemporary Public and Private Records. Cyril Bathurst Judge (1935) Res v. 12 n. 48 October 1936. (Box 1)
  - The Early English Carols. Richard Leighton Greene (Ed.) (1935) Res v. 13 n. 49 January 1937. (Box 1)
  - Shakespeare and the Post-Horses: A New Study of "The Merry Wives of Windsor." J. Crofts (1937) Res v. 14 n. 53 January 1938. (Box 1)
  - The Tragedy of Hamlet, A Critical Edition of the Second Quarto, 1604, with an Introduction and Textual Notes. Parrot and Craig (1938) Res v. 15 n. 58 April 1938. (Box 1)
  - The True Text of "King Lear". Leo Kirschbaum (1945) Res v. 22 n. 87 July 1946. (Box 1)
  - The Bad Quarto of "Romeo and Juliet": A Bibliographical and Textual Study. Harry R. Hoppe (1948) Res v. 1 n. 1 1950. (Box 1)
  - English Institute Annual: 1941. (1942) Res v. 19 n. 75 July 1943. (Box 1)
  - A Pleasaunte & Merrye Humor of a Roge. Francis Needham (Ed.) (1933) Bodleian Quarterly Record v. VII n. 81 April 1934. (Box 1)
  - On Editing Shakespeare and the Elizabethan Dramatists. Fredson Bowers (1955) Shakespeare Quarterly v. VII n. 1 Winter 1956. (Box 1)
  - Shakespeare's "Love's Labor's Won." T.W. Baldwin (1957). (Box 1)
  - Titus Andronicus. J.C. Maxwell (Ed.) (1953). (Box 1)
  - The Struggle for Freedom of the Press from Caxton to Cromwell. William M. Clyde (1934) The Modern Language Review v. XXX n. 4 October 1935. (Box 1)
  - The Plays of John Marston. H. Harvey Wood (Ed.) Vol. 1 (1934) MLR v. XXX n. 1 January 1935. (Box 1)
  - The Manuscript of Shakespeare's "Hamlet" and the Problems of its Transmission. J. Dover Wilson (1934) MLR v. XXX n. 1 January 1935. (Box 1)
  - The Lost Plays and Masques 1500-1642. Gertrude Marian Sibley MLR v. XXIX n. 2 April 1934. (Box 1)
  - A Dialogue Concerning Witches and Witchcraft, 1593 et. al. [Shakespeare Association, G.B. Harrison, Ed.] 1931. MLR v. XXVII n. 3 July 1932. (Box 1)
  - Shakespeare Versus Shallow. Leslie Hotson (1931) MLR v. XXVII n. 2 April 1932. (Box 1)
  - The Seventeenth Earl of Oxford, 1550-1604 From Contemporary Documents. D.M. Ward (1928) MLR v. XXIV n. 2 April 1929. (Box 1)
  - Some 'Echoes' in Elizabethan Drama of Shakespeare's "King Henry the Fourth", Parts I and II, Considered in Relation to the Text of Those Plays. R.D. Cowl (1926) MLR v. XXIII n. 1 January 1928. (Box 1)
  - The Child Actors, A Chapter in Elizabethan Stage History. H.N. Hillebrand (1926) MLR v. XXIII n. 1 January 1928. (Box 1)
  - Sidelights on Elizabethan Drama. H. Dugdale Sykes (1924) MLR v. XX n. 2 April 1925. (Box 1)
  - The Text of Shakespeare's Hamlet. B.A.P. Van Dam M.D. (1924) MLR v. XX n. 1 January 1925. (Box 1)
  - Pearl, Cleanness, Patience and Sir Gawain. Sir I. Gollancz (Ed.) MLR v. XIX n. 2 April 1924. (Box 1)
  - Hamlet: Its Textual History. H. DeGroot (1923) MLR v. XIX n. 2 April 1924. (Box 1)
  - Studies in the Development of the Fool in the Elizabethan Drama. Olive Mary Busby (1923) MLR v. XIX n. 2 April 1924. (Box 1)
  - The Works of Shakespeare. Quiller-Couch and Wilson (Eds.) Vol. 1 (1921) MLR v. XVII n. 2 April 1922. (Box 1)
  - Shakespeare - Worterbuch. Leon Keuner (1922) MLR v. XVIII n. 2 April 1923. (Box 1)
  - The Comedy of Acolastus. P.L. Carver (Ed.) (1937) MLR v. XXXII n. 4 October 1937. (Box 1)
  - Early English Versions of the Tales of Guiscardo and Ghismonda and Titus and Gisippus from the Decameron. Herbert G. Wright (Ed.) (1937) MLR v. XXXIII n. 3 July 1938. (Box 1)
  - Bibliographical Description and Cataloging. J.D. Cowley (1939) MLR v. XXXV n. 2 April 1940. (Box 1)
  - John Milton's Complete Poetical Works Reproduced in Photographic Facsimile. Harris Francis Fletcher (Ed.) Vol. 1 (1943) MLR v. XXXIX n. 4 October 1944. (Box 1)
  - The Statistical Study of Literary Vocabulary. G. Undy Yule (1944) MLR v. XXXIX n. 3 July 1944. (Box 1)
  - IBID Vol. II (1945) MLR v. XLII n. 1 January 1947. (Box 1)
  - Mysteries and Investigation of the Last Days of the Medieval Religious Stage. Harold C. Gardiner (1946) MLR. (Box 1)
  - The Passionate Pilgrim by William Shakespeare. Joseph Quincy Adams (Ed.) Modern Language Notes v. LV n. 6 June 1940. (Box 1)
  - The Phoenix Nest, 1593. Hyder Edward Rollins. Modern Language Notes 47 2 February 1932. (Box 1)
  - Shakespeare's 'King Lear': A critical Edition. George Ian Duthie (Ed.) 1949 MLR v. XLIV n. 3 July 1949. [Proof Copy]. (Box 1)
  - The Great Folio of 1623: Shakespeare's Plays in the Printing House. John W. Schroeder [cf. Also Box 2, Folder 1] The Library v. 12 n. 2 June 1957. (Box 1)
- Personal Copies of Colleagues' Articles, 1921-1960; Series II; 0.42; (1 box)
  Arranged alphabetically by name of reviewer.
  Series II contains articles by friends and colleagues of Greg, some with annotations by the authors and/or by Greg. Several are presentation copies.
  - Joseph Quincy Adams, "The Folger Shakespeare Memorial Library A Report on Progress, 1931-1941," [Insc. to WWG]., 1942 (Box 2)
  - The Bibliographical Society of America v. 36. [Notes by WWG]., 1942 (Box 2)
  - R.C. Bald "Early Copyright Litigation and its Bibliographical Interest," The Bibliographical Society of America v. 36. [Notes by WWG]., 1942 (Box 2)
  - Gerald Eades Bentley, "The Swan of Avon and the Bricklayer of Westminster: [Insc. to WWG]., 1946 March 15 (Box 2)
  - Bodleian Library, "The Opening of the New Library by His Majesty King George VI" [Invitation to WWG, Program, Off- Print from Library Record laid in]., 1946 October 24 (Box 2)
  - Fredson Bowers, "The Textual Relation of Q2 to Q1 Hamlet (1)" Studies in Bibliography V. VIII, [Insc. to WWG; Notes by WWG]., 1956 (Box 2)
  - Fredson Bowers, "Robert Roberts: A Printer of Shakespeare's Fourth Folio" Shakespeare Quarterly v. II n. 3, [Insc. to WWG]., 1951 July (Box 2)
  - Tucker Brooke, "Elizabethan Proof Corrections in a Copy of The First Part of Contention 1600" Huntington Library Bulletin N. 2, [Insc. to WWG; Notes by WWG; Article laid in]., 1931 November (Box 2)
  - Cantrell and Williams, "Roberts' Compositors in Titus Andronicus Q2" Studies in Bibliography V. VIII [Notes by WWG]., 1956 (Box 2)
  - Sir Edmund Craster, "John Rous, Bodley's Librarian 1620-52" The Bodleian Library Record v. V n. 3, [Notes by WWG]., 1955 July (Box 2)
  - John Crow, "Editing and Emending" Essays and Studies, [Insc. to WWG; Frag Regarding "Scilens" in Marston laid in]., 1955 (Box 2)
  - John Crow, "Folklore in Elizabethan Drama" Folk-Lore v. LVIII, [Insc. to WWG; Notes by WWG]., 1947 September (Box 2)
  - R.W. Chambers, "King Lear" Glasgow [Insc. to WWG; Clipping from Times 12 Nov 1941 & Correspondence from Chambers to WWG 6 Nov 1940 Laid in]. (Box 2)
  - Helen Darbishire, "Milton's Paradise Lost" London, [Insc. to WWG]., 1951 (Box 2)
  - Una Ellis-Fermor, "The Study of Shakespeare" London, [Insc. to WWG]., 1948 (Box 2)
  - Richard Flatter, "'The True Original Copies' of Shakespeare's Plays Outline of a New Conception" Proceedings of the Leeds Philo- sophical Society v. VII Part 1, [Insc. to WWG; Notes by WWG; Correspondences Dated 8 Aug l952 and Aug 1952 to WWG from Flatter Laid In]., 1952 July (Box 2)
  - Ephim G. Fogel, "'A Table of Green Fields' A Defense of the Folio Reading" Shakespeare Quarterly v. IX n. 4, [Insc. to WWG]., 1958 August (Box 2)
  - Frost and Nash, " Good Order: A Morality Fragment" Studies in Philology v. XLI n. 4. [cf. Box 10 Folder 2 for photostat of Frag]., 1944 October (Box 2)
  - Charlton Hinman, Review of John W. Schroeder's The Great Folio of 1623: Shakespeare's Plays in the Printing House. Shakespeare Quarterly v. VIII n. 2, [Greg's Review lain in; cf. Box 1 Folder 1]., 1957 Spring (Box 2)
  - Leslie Hotson, "Shakespeare's Arena" The Sewanee Review, [Insc. to WWG]., 1952 July (Box 2)
  - R.G. Howarth, "The Life of Literature". Typescript., 1956 (Box 2)
  - R.G. Howarth, "Two Elizabethan Writers of Fiction, Thomas Nashe and Thomas Deloney: Capetown, [Insc. to WWG]., 1956 (Box 2)
  - Harold Jantz, "An Elizabethan Statement on the Origin of the German Faust Book" The Journal of English and Germanic Philology v. LI n. 2, [Insc. to WWG]., 1952 April (Box 2)
  - Robert Alger Law, "Holinshed's Leir Story and Shakespeare's" Studies in Philology v. XLVII n. 1, [Insc. to WWG]., 1950 January (Box 2)
  - J.G. McManaway, "Bibliography", 1955. (Box 2)
  - R.B. McKerrow, "A Note on the Teaching of 'English Language and Literature' with Some Suggestions" The English Association., 1921 June (Box 2)
  - Paul Mass, "Editorial Problems in Shakespeare" Res v. XIX n. 76, [Letter to WWG laid in, Dated 18 Jun 1944; Response by WWG Laid in, Res V. 20 1944., 1943 October (Box 2)
  - Paul Mass, "Einleitung in die Altertumwissenschaft" B.G. Teubner I Band, 2 Heft, [Insc to WWG Jan 18, 1941]., 1927 (Box 2)
  - Reginald Poole, "The Beginning of the Year in the Middle Ages" Proceedings of The British Academy v. I., 1921 (Box 2)
  - George R. Price, "The Manuscript and the Quarto of The Roaring Girl " London, [Insc. to WWG; Notes by WWG]., 1956 (Box 2)
  - H.T. Price, "Towards a Scientific Method of Textual Criticism for the Elizabethan Drama" The Journal of English and Germanic Philology v. XXXVI n. 2, [notes by WWG]., 1937 April (Box 2)
  - The Rosenbaum Company, "English Plays to 1700" New York [Notes by WWG]., 1940 (Box 2)
  - The Rosenbaum Company, "English Poetry to 1700" New York., 1941 (Box 2)
  - The Rosenbaum Company, "William Shakespeare A Collection of First and Early Editions of His Works 1594 to 1700" New York, [Corres- pondence from Wm. H. McCarthy laid in]., 1951 (Box 2)
  - Levin L. Schuking, "Uber Einige Problem der Neueren und Neusten Shakespeare-Forschung" Germanisch- Romanische Monatschrift Band II Heft 3, [Insc. to WWG]., 1952 May (Box 2)
  - John Harrington Smith, "The Dryden-Howard Collaboration" Studies in Philology v. LI n. 1 [Notes by WWG]., 1954 January (Box 2)
  - James R. Sutherland, "The English Critic" London, [Insc to WWG]., 1952 (Box 2)
  - F.P. Wilson, "Sir Walter Wilson Greg 1875-1959 Proceedings of the British Academy v. XLV, [Insc. "Jim from David 26 VIII 60]., 1960 (Box 2)
  - Louis B. Wright, "The Reading of Plays During the Puritan Revolution" Huntington Library Bulletin n. 6, [Reprint from Library Journal 1 Sep 1934 laid in]., 1934 November (Box 2)
- Contributions to The Modern Language Review Volumes I-XV., 1905-1920; Series III; 1
  Chronologically arranged.
  Bound volumes containing copies of all of Greg's contributions to The Modern Language Review ( MLR). Some notes and articles may be annotated by Greg.
  - 1. Lyly's Plays" v. I n. 1. "The Authorship of the Songs in Lyly" (Box 3)
  - 2. "Recent Work on the Elizabethan Drama" (Review) v. I n. 2. (Box 3)
  - 3. "The Plays and Poems of Robert Greene: (Review) v. I n. 3. (Box 3)
  - 4. Note on "Specimens of the Elizabethan Drama v. I n. 4. (Box 3)
  - 5. "Jonson's 'Staple of News' v. I n. 4. (Box 3)
  - 6. "Did Shakespeare Write 'Titus Andronicus'?" (Review) v. I n. 4. (Box 3)
  - 7. "John Webster" (Review) v. II n. 1. (Box 3)
  - 8. "La Pastoral Dramatique en France" (Review) v. II n. 1. (Box 3)
  - 9. "Drayton's Sonnets" v. II n. 2. (Box 3)
  - 10. "Versification Francaise et Anglaise" (Review) v. II n. 2. (Box 3)
  - 11. John Fletcher (Review) v. II n. 4. (Box 3)
  - 12. Giovanna D'Aragona (Review) v. II n. 4., 1907 July (Box 3)
  - 13. Cupid's Revenge (Review) v. II n. 4., 1907 July (Box 3)
  - 14. The Queen or the Excellency of Her Sex (Review) v. II n. 4., 1907 July (Box 3)
  - 15. The Hector of Germany (Review) v. III n. 4., 1908 April (Box 3)
  - 16. English Miracles and Moralities (Review) v. III n. 4., 1908 July (Box 3)
  - 17. An Interlude of Welth and Helth (Review) v. IV n. 1., 1908 October (Box 3)
  - 18. The Partial Law (Review) v. IV n. 1., 1908 October (Box 3)
  - 19. Shakespeare's 'Sonnets' and 'A Lover's Complaint' (Review) v. IV n. 1., 1908 October (Box 3)
  - 20. Club Law (Review) v. IV n. 2., 1909 April (Box 3)
  - 21. The New Inn (Review) v. IV n. 2., 1909 April (Box 3)
  - 22. The Knight of the Burning Pestle (Review) v. IV n. 3., 1909 April (Box 3)
  - 23. "The Hamlet Quartos 1603, 1604" v. VI n. 3., 1909 April (Box 3)
  - 24. Elizabethan Drama, 1558-1642 (Review) v. V n. 2., 1910 April (Box 3)
  - 25. "The Troubles of a Norman Scribe" v. V n. 3., 1910 July (Box 3)
  - 26. Hymenaeus and Fucus Histriomastix (Reviews) v. V n. 3., 1910 July (Box 3)
  - 27. Note on "Greene's Plays" v. V n. 3., 1910 July (Box 3)
  - 28. The Chronicle History of King Leir (Review) v. V n. 4., 1910 October (Box 3)
  - 29. Laelia (Review) v. VI n. 4., 1911 October (Box 3)
  - 30. Les Masques Anglais (Review) v. VI n. 4., 1911 October (Box 3)
  - 31. Elizabethan Drama: Notes and Studies (Review) v. VI n. 4., 1911 October (Box 3)
  - 32. Government Regulation of the Elizabethan Drama (Review) v. VI n. 4., 1911 October (Box 3)
  - 33. "A Ballad of Twelfth Day" v. VIIII n. 1., 1913 January (Box 3)
  - 34. Note on Autograph Plays by Anthony Munday" v. VIII n. 1., 1913 January (Box 3)
  - 35. Note on "Chaucer Attributions... in Trinity College Library" v. VIII n. 4., 1913 October (Box 3)
  - 36."A Ballad of Twelfth Day" (Additions) v. IX n. 2., 1914 April (Box 3)
  - 37. Cynthia's Revels (Review) v. IX n. 2., 1914 April (Box 3)
  - 38. "Hamlet's Hallucination" v. XII n. 4., 1917 October (Box 3)
  - 39. Englishmen For My Money (Review) v. XIII n. 1., 1918 January (Box 3)
  - 40. Note on 'Titus Andronicus' v. XIV n. 3., 1919 July (Box 3)
  - 41. "Re-Enter Ghost a Reply to Mr. J. Dover Wilson" v. XIV n. 4., 1919 October (Box 3)
  - 42. "The 'Hamlet' Texts and Recent Work in Shakespearean Bibliography" v. XIV n. 4., 1919 October (Box 3)
  - 43. Ordo Rachelis (Review) v. XV n. 4., 1920 October (Box 3)
  - 44. The Stonyhurst Pageants (Review) v. XV n. 4., 1920 October (Box 3)
- Greg's Contributions to The Library, Volumes I-X, 1900-1909; Series IV; 1
  Material mostly chronologically arranged by date of publication.
  Series IV contains Greg's contributions to the periodical The Library. Some may be annotated by Greg.
  - 1. "Bacon's Biliteral Cipher and its Applications" v. III n. 1. (Box 3)
  - 2. "Old Plays and New Editions" v. III n. 4. (Box 3)
  - 3. "Facts and Fancies in Baconian Theory" v. IV n. 1. (Box 3)
  - 4. "The Bibliographical History of the First Folio" v. IV n. 3. (Box 3)
  - 5. "Tottel's Miscellany" v. V n. 18 [cf. v. 3]. (Box 3)
  - 6. "Henslowe, Collier, and the latest German Criticism" v. V n. 3. (Box 3)
  - 7. "Two Reviews" v. Vll n. 1. (Box 3)
  - 8. "On Certain False Dates in Shakespearean Quartos" v. IX n. 2. (Box 3)
  - 9. "On the Supposed False Dates in Certain Shakespearean Quartos" (Huth) (Pollard), v. IX n. 4. (Box 3)
  - 10. "False Dates in Shakespearean Quartos" (A.W. Pollard)., undated (Box 3)
  - 11. "Another Baconian Cipher" v. X n. 4., 1909 October (Box 3)
- Greg's Personal Copy of Gentleman's Magazine, Volume CCC, 1906, undated; Series V; 1
  Copy of the June 1906 edition of Gentleman's Magazine, annotated by Greg.
  - 1. "Prince Henry's Players" p. 67 [Notes by WWG]. (Box 3)
  - 2. "Sir Henry Herbert's Office-Book" p. 72. (Box 3)
  - 3. "Here's A Farmer, That Hang'd Himselfe on Th' Expectation of Plentie" p. 305. (Box 3)
- Plates I-CXXXVII From Volume I of Bibliography of English Printed Drama., [circa 1939-1959, undated]; Series VI; 0.21; (1 box)
  Arranged by plate number (series not complete).
  Plates used by Greg in Volume I of Bibliography of English Printed Drama.
  - Plates Appear in Numerical Order (Box 4)
- Prints of Title Pages and Portraits, circa 1800-1959, undated; Series VII; 0.21; (1 box)
  Material arranged in no particular order.
  Greg's collection of engraved and printed portraits of English authors, as well as some title pages.